Tejas Hedly

Ph: +91-8904429443

Email: tejas.240489@gmail.com

DOB: 24th April 1989

PROFILE

I am a proficient developer with 2 years' of commercial experience and a track record of delivering quality solutions using a range of different technologies. I am also a keen proponent of agile methodologies and have successfully worked on projects using it. I have sufficient knowledge in retail banking and I am currently working as a front end developer designing interfaces to a banking system at Achumen Technologies Private Limited.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Electrical & Electronics, Visveswaraya technological University, Bangalore, India, 2011

Diploma in java, NIIT Koramanagala, Bangalore, India, 2012, 6 months

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

• Oracle certified professional, java SE 6, effective from April 30th 2012.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Php scripting
- Core Java
- Open source libraries (Django, Codeigniter, JavaScript infovis toolkit, Morris charts, SVN, GIT, JSON, XML)
- Javascript / Jquery / Ajax
- HTML / CSS
- Tastypie REST Web services
- Web / Application Servers (Apache, Tomcat, IIS)
- Database Servers (Oracle, MSSQL, MySQL)
- Operating Systems (Windows7, Ubuntu)
- Fair knowledge on mobile application development using Android & Kivy
- Web and Application Security
- WPF / Windows Forms
- Standard banks link / UML / Workflow designer
- Programming Architectures (MVC, MVT, MVVM)

EXPERIENCE

Standard Banks Link. Capitec Bank, September 2013 – February 2014 Front End Developer

- Developed the front end screens for a web portal, which uses core banking system for different transactions, using xHTML, CSS, XML, Workflow designer & Javascript
- Currently Integrating the Amaqele biometrics framework with the web portal using ActiveX components. This framework is used by a fingerprint reader to verify the different types of users. The ActiveX component was developed using C# on .NET 3.5 framework.
- A batch file was also written to register this ActiveX component on all branch machines. An msi installer for the same is also being developed.

XperienceBox.

Achumen Technologies Pvt.Ltd., Bangalore. March 2013 – September 2013 Senior Web Developer

- A web application to capture the end user's information, issues, concerns, feedback and platform to share their experience.
- The target audiences will get rational information confined using business intelligence determining the company group or customer group who enrich the quality services to their end consumers.
- Understanding of Business requirement of this project.
- Analysis of functional and non functional requirements.
- Discussions and clarifications with Business Analyst.
- Involved in Design and architecture of the solution
- Development of core functionalities using Python-Django, Tastypie, JSON, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JQUERY.
- Followed the product development lifecycle.
- Responsible for creating reports and graphical charts using open source tools.
- Perform thorough testing on the functionalities developed.
- Bug fixing and Documentation.

Kreativ Lab.

Logic And Madness Creative Labs Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore. , August 2012 Web Developer

- This website showcases the different programs offered by the Kreativ Lab school of animation.
- The programs offered are on different study levels from the intensive "School of Thought" program at schools to high quality professional "Cretique" program in animation & design. This website is also incorporated with a content management system
- I was involved in the Discussions and clarifications with the Clients.
- Design and architecture of the solution
- Responsible for creating Layouts using HTML, CSS and JQUERY

- Designed and developed the admin panel for content management using HTML, CSS, PHP and JQUERY.
- Unit testing on the functionalities developed.
- Bug fixing and Documentation.

GetActive.

2mpower Health Management Services Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore., October 2012
Front end Developer

- This is Health Management System which analyses the daily physical activities of a user.
- The portal provides data charts which give details about monthly and weekly status of health activities.
- I was involved in Understanding of Business requirement of this project.
- Discussions and clarifications with the Clients.
- Front end validations for various forms.
- Responsible for creating reports and graphical charts using open source tools.
- Perform thorough testing on the functionalities developed.
- Bug fixing and Documentation.

Leocon. Leomining company, Bangalore. June 2012 – July 2012 Web Developer

- Leocon is an application which is used to manage financial data using reports and charts.
- It also provides a communication medium for board members of company to communicate amongst each other.
- The Financial Module within the portal provides daily expense reports about various mining related expenses.
- I was involved in Understanding of Business requirement of this project.
- Analysis of functional and non functional requirements.
- Discussions and clarifications with the clients.
- Designed the database structure and was responsible for creating stored procedures.
- Development of core functionalities using PHP, JSON and MySQL.
- Developed the Front end Layouts, functionalities and various form validations using HTML, CSS and JQUERY
- Followed the product development lifecycle.
- Unit testing on the functionalities developed.
- Bug fixing and Documentation.

Yahvi Home solutions. Yahvi Home solutions, Bangalore. October 2011 – May 2012 Web Developer

- Yahvi home solution is an application developed on a PHP framework.
- It is an online property portal where users can check for available properties in the city. This portal was hosted on a shared apache server.

- Analysis of functional and non functional requirements.
- Discussions and clarifications with the clients.
- Designed the database structure and was responsible for creating stored procedures.
- Development of core functionalities using PHP, JSON and MySQL.
- Front end Layouts, functionalities and validations using HTML, CSS and JQUERY
- Followed the product development lifecycle.
- Thorough testing on the functionalities developed.
- Bug fixing and Documentation.

HOBBIES / INTERESTS

- Cycling sport
- Trekking
- Ethical Hacking & Cryptography.

ACTIVITIES

- House captain (December 2004 December 2005)
- Class Representative (September 2007 December 2010)
- Placement coordinator (January 2011 February 2011)
- Member of the volleyball team, representing Bangalore (March 2000 April 2002, September 2005 October 2007)